Marie Reine Bienaimee

Rwanda | Kigali- Gasabo | +250790840767 bienaimeemariereine@gmail.com |https://www.linkedin.com/in/marie-reine-bienaimee-a611a6270/

SUMMARY

Marie Reine BIENAIMEE is a dynamic and proficient Backend developer with a passion for crafting elegant and efficient software solutions. With a keen eye for detail and a dedication to staying at the forefront of technological advancements,

Marie Reine brings a unique blend of creativity and technical expertise to every project she undertakes.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

African Leadership University - Kigali, Rwanda

Jan 2023 - Now

Bachelor degree

Software Engineering

I have a strong foundation in web development (front-end & back-end), Linux, Python, JavaScript,php, database and core programming fundamentals.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intern at Toast group

May 2023-sept 2023

I was web developer intern helping their trainees to be aware of web development

Participant

Feb 2024-May 2024

SheCanCode Program- Kigali, Rwanda

I enrolled in the SheCanCode program, which is a rigorous 4-month intensive training program. The program is specifically designed to equip young women with essential skills in back-end web development. During my participation, I am focusing on mastering the fundamentals of back-end development, and I am currently gaining proficiency in JavaScript, Express, Node.JS, MongoBD, and Swagger

SKILLS

•Microsoft Exel - Excellent	•HTML&CSS - Excellent	•Express - Excellent
•Microsoft Word - Excellent	JavaScript - Excellent	Python - Good
•Solidwork - Excellent		Node.js -Excellent

INTERESTS

• Job Creation	Women Empowerment	 Technology 	And
		Conservetion	

LANGUAGES

●Kinyarwanda- Excellent ●English- Excellent ●French- Beginner

• deutch-intermediate

REFERENCES

•	Herve Musangwa	Facilitator at ALU	Email: h.musangwa@alueducation.com
•	Alex Habimana	Supervisor at ALU	Email:habimalexis@gmail.com